Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- DeSantis, Dennis, February 2015-ongoing; 4 websites in 4 archived websites
  Dennis DeSantis (b. 1973) is a composer, sound designer, percussionist, author, and educator. He is the Head of Music Learning for Ableton, an online resource for learning the fundamentals of music making through the use of beats, melodies, harmonies, basslines, and song structures. DeSantis previously worked as a sound designer for Native Instruments. He has also organized and produced concerts and multimedia events with the Alarm Will Sound ensemble and the Minimum Security Composers Collective.
- Dessner, Bryce, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5919; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of brycedessner.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; news related to Dessner's work; a list of compositions; past and upcoming performances; press articles; and information on different projects such as film soundtracks and albums.
  Bryce Dessner (b. 1976) is an American composer, songwriter, and guitarist based in Paris. His classical music compositions include music for large ensembles, orchestra, chamber, and vocal music. Dessner is also a founding member of the American rock band The National. As a composer, he has written scores for major film productions including such titles as The Two Popes, The Revenant, and C'mon C'mon.
- Deyoe, Nicholas, February 2015-July 2020; cuid5910; Deyoe, Nicholas, 1981-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of nicholasdeyoe.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The crawl was rescoped in an attempt to also capture SoundCloud audio files.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; information on the concert series wasteLAnd and KillDry Dark, his ambient electric guitar project with Jay Sorce; a list of his works as a composer, conductor, and guitarist; a discography of his work as an audio engineer; information about his role as a conductor; and contact information.
  Nicholas Deyoe (b. 1981) is a composer and guitarist based in Los Angeles who experiments with different sounds and equipment to create his music, including microtonal tunings, preparation, bows, and cans. Deyoe is a co-founder of the ensemble and concert series wasteLAnd; and formed part of KillDry, a dark-ambient electric guitar duo with musician Jay Sorce. He is also a member of Serpentine Transmission, an improvised music quartet.
- Diaz de León, Mario, February 2015-ongoing; 3 websites in 3 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of mariodiazdeleon.com, mariodiazdeleon.blogspot.com, and ikatmethod.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of March 2025, the website contains a biography; a listing of his events; his discography; description and audio of his works; video of performances; and contact information. Included here is also a capture of his defunct blog.
  Mario Diaz de León (b. 1979) is a composer and performer, whose work explores the intersections of sound, spirituality, and technology, and encompasses modern classical music, experimental electronic music, extreme metal, and creative improvised music. Diaz de León works as a solo artist, as well as in collaborations with other musicians. He is a part of the duo Luminous Vault and the improvisation trio Bloodmist. He has also released heavy ambient electronic music under the stage name Oneirogen. Recent works by Diaz de León include Tree of Life (2024), Procession (2023), and Labrys (2017).
- Dicke, Ian, February 2014-ongoing; Dicke, Ian, 1982-; 3 websites in 3 archived websites
  The website contains his biography, a portfolio of his music, music software, samples of his music, and a calendar of performances. Novel Music is the landing page for his music software projects, including Seeds, Deviate, Melodia, Linea, and Rhythmicana. His web presence also includes a website for his opera, Roman.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of iandicke.com, romanopera.com, and novelmusic.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Scope was expanded to include SoundCloud.
  Ian Dicke (b. 1982) is an American composer and educator inspired by social-political culture and interactive technology. Dicke was the founder and curator of the Outpost Concert Stories in Riverside California between 2013 and 2023. He is also a Professor of Composition at the University of California Riverside. His compositions include pieces for orchestra, wind ensemble, opera, chamber, solo, and piano. He is also a developer of musical software.
- Didkovsky, Nick, June 2017-ongoing; cuid5874; 6 websites in 6 archived websites
  In order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints, crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of didkovsky.com, as well as four external websites which were included due to their contextual value to the site that is the focus of this crawl. These websites are: doctornerve.org, vomitfist.com, busterandfriends.com/projects/eris, and punosmusic.com.
  As of April 2025, Didkovsky's personal website features a biography of the artist; a list of the bands he is involved with; a list of projects; information about his software developments including the Java Music Specification Language and MaxScore; and a link to the website of his record label Punos Music. The archived websites also include specific projects or musical groups in which Didkovsky has been involved with including Doctor Nerve; Vomit First; Eris 136199; and Didkovsky's 2015 residency at The Stone, a venue for the performance of experimental music located in New York City. The archived website for Punos Music Records was also crawled.
  Nick Didkovsky (b. 1958) is guitarist, composer, and music software programmer. The focus of his work is primarily on rock music. He has played in such musical groups as Vomit Fist; the Fred Frith Guitar Quartet; and Doctor Nerve, a band that he founded in 1983. Didkovsky is the co-creator of the Java Music Specification Language (JMSL), a Java API that he uses to teach algorithmic music composition at New York University. He is also the founder of the record label Punos Music, through which he releases "extreme musical projects."
- Diels, Natacha, April 2014-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  The website contained performance listings; links to music; program notes; teaching and course descriptions; images; and a calendar. In 2020, the URL changed and the website was reformatted. As of 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist, examples of Diels' works in the form of embedded video files, a list of works, a link to the composer's Vimeo account, and her contact information.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of natachadiels.com and natachapop.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Natacha Diels (b. 1981) is a performing and composing musician from New Mexico. She founded the experimental chamber group Ensemble Pamplemousse, which also includes David Broome, Andrew Greenwald, Bryan Jacobs, and Weston Olencki. Diels' work combines choreographed movement, improvisation, video, instrumental practice, and cynical play. In recent works such as Beautiful Trouble (2019-2024) and Somewhere Beautiful (2022-2024), Diels collaborated with the JACK Quartet, an American group dedicated to the performance of contemporary classical music.
- Dooley, Paul, April 2014-ongoing; Dooley, Paul, 1983-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  The website contains a biography of the artist; a list of his compositions; concert listings; scores for purchase; photos of the artist and his collaborators; and contact information. His web presence also includes the website for The Conductor's Spellbook, an orchestral work designed for young audiences by Paul Dooley and illustrations by Tanner Porter.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of conductorsspellbook.com and pauldooley.net in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Paul Dooley (b. 1983) is an orchestral composer focusing on a "cross-cultural range of contemporary music, dance, art, technology and the interactions between the human and natural worlds." Some of Dooley's recent works include Circuits and Skins (2017), which is an EDM-inspired electronic percussion concerto; Mondrian's Studio (2019), a work for horn and wind ensemble; and the Conductor's Spellbook (2016), an educational and interactive work for young audiences.
- Doty, David B., February 2014- ongoing; cuid5896; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.dbdoty.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist and resume; a list of his musical compositions; writings; and information on his other interests.
  Embedded video and audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  David B. Doty (b. 1950) is a composer who specializes in just intonation, experimenting with various instruments, synthesizers, and samplers. Doty is the author of The Just Intonation Primer, and introductory book on the theory and practice of Just Intonation. He was also the co-founder of The Just Intonation Network in Northern California.
- Dresser, Mark, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5875; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of www.mark-dresser.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; information about past and upcoming events; news about the artist including announcements of his album releases; reviews of Dresser's work; a discography; information about his works and projects accompanied by embedded video files; and contact information.
  Mark Dresser (b. 1952) is a bassist and composer who has been a part of many musical groups and also works as a solo performer of the contrabass. Solo releases by Dresser include such works as GUTS: Bass Explorations, Investigations, and Explanations, UNVEIL, and Invocation. In 2007, Dresser started focusing on the research, performance, composition, and teaching of telematic music, which "explores the musical, technical, and social dimensions of live performance between multiple locations through high speed internet." Examples of his telematic internet performances include Deep Tones for Peace and ResoNations. Besides performing as a solo bassist, Dresser is also a current member of the collective Trio M.
- Dreyblatt, Arnold, June 2017-ongoing; cuid5870; 3 websites in 3 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of dreyblatt.net in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the composer's website features information about his roles as a media artist and composer. It includes information about his multiple projects and collaborations accompanied by images and embedded audio and video files; his discography; information about his teaching; his curriculum vitae; a calendar of events; and contact information. The archived websites also include two of Dreyblatt's projects titled Who's Who In Central and Eastern Europe 1933 and The Memory Arena.
  Who's Who In Central and Eastern Europe 1933 was originally realized as a "Hypertext Opera" in co-production of the Inventionen '91, the Berliner Artist Program of the DAAD, and the Wiener Fest Wochen. The world premiere took place on February 13, 1991 in Kino Babylon in Berlin. This website highlights the 765 people from the original book the opera is based on and uses hyperlinks to connect the individuals to related categories instead of a static alphabetical list.
  The Memory Arena (1995-1996) was a performance installation created by Dreyblatt. The website was built in collaboration with historian Martin Warnke and students at the University of Lüneburg, Germany. It depicts a series of stages that crowds had to walk through in the live performance, which represented the administrative functions of a large bureaucracy.
  Arnold Dreyblatt (b. 1953) is a Berlin-based American artist, and a member of the second generation of New York minimal composers. Dreyblatt has invented a variety of instruments and new techniques for tuning and playing traditional instruments in order to make his music and performance art. As a media artist, his work engages with archival materials and historical artifacts. As a composer, Dreyblatt's music primarily focuses on the exploration of the harmonic series. Dreyblatt was the founder of The Orchestra of Excited Strings, which originated in New York City in 1979.
- Du, Yun, April 2014-ongoing; Du, Yun, 1977-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of channelduyun.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Du Yun (b. 1977) is a New York City-based composer, instrumentalist, performer, and multimedia artist born in Shanghai, China. Her work includes orchestral, opera, and chamber music, and incorporates theater, cabaret, oral traditions, and visual arts. Du Yun's second opera, Angel's Bone, was awarded a Pulitzer Prize for music in 2017. Other notable works by Du Yun include her studio albums Sweet Land, A Cockroach's Tarantella, and Dinosaur Scar. She is also the leader of the band Ok Miss, which doubles as a rock band and a chamber ensemble, and a founding member of the International Contemporary Ensemble (ICE).
  As of March 2025, the website contains a biography; a list of her works with descriptions and embedded media; information about Future Tradition, a collective project led by Du Yun in collaboration with artists and musicians from different parts of the world; information about her work as a curator of music; news about the artist; a list of her album releases; a calendar of events; press coverage about Du Yun's work including quotes, features in different publications, and interviews; and contact information.
- DuBois, R. Luke, February 2015-November 2017; Dubois, R. Luke; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of lukedubois.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  R. Luke DuBois (b. 1975) is a New York City-based composer, performer, multimedia artist, and photographer. In his works, DuBois uses data-driven techniques to investigate time, memory, identity, and the meaning of portraiture in the United States in the twenty-first century. DuBois is a member of multiple musical groups, including the avant-garde electronic group The Freight Elevator Quartet, the duo Bioluminescence with vocalist Lesley Flanigan, and the Fair Use Trio with Zach Layton and Matthew Ostrowski. He is also the director for the Brooklyn Experimental Media Center at NYU Tandon and the co-author of Jitter, a software suite for real-time manipulation of matrix data.
  The website features DuBois' past and present projects; a calendar of events; a list of collaborators; a biography; and contact information.
- Duckworth, William, February 2015; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of billduckworth.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  William "Bill" Duckworth (1943-2012) was a composer, performer, and pioneer of postminimalist music best known for choral pieces and piano cycles. Duckworth's works also included interactive electronic projects using the Internet. His series of 24 short pieces for piano titled The Time Curve Preludes is considered the first postminimal music composition. Other notable works by Duckworth include Southern Harmony, Mysterious Number, Imaginary Dances, Simple Songs About Sex and War, and Cathedral, an internet piece created in 1997.
  The website was captured one time in February 2015. It contained a biography of the artist, and information on his compositions and writings. As of 2024, the website no longer exists online.
- Eckardt, Jason, June 2017-ongoing; cuid5920; Eckardt, Jason, 1971-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ensemble21.com/eckardt/home.html and jasoneckardt.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; a list of his musical compositions and recordings; examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files; a discography; and contact information.
  Jason Eckardt (b. 1971) is a composer of music influenced by his interests in political activism, the natural world, and performance. His compositions include chamber, solo, vocal, and orchestral music. Examples of notable works by Eckardt include Subject, Undersong, Out of Chaos, and Wild Ginger. Before delving fully into his role as a composer, Eckardt played guitar in jazz and metal bands. He was also a co-founder of Ensemble 21, a New York City-based contemporary music performance group.
  As of November 2019, the composer's website moved to the URL https://www.jasoneckardt.com, which is now the focus of this crawl.
- Eckert, Rinde, February 2015-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of rindeeckert.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Rinde Eckert (b. 1951) is a writer, composer, and librettist. The principal focus of Eckert's repertoire is the creation of Opera and New Music Theatre productions. In 2012, he was awarded a Grammy Award for his recording of Lonely Motel: Music from Slide, in collaboration with Steven Mackey and the Eighth Blackbird ensemble. Other notable works by Eckert include Breathing at the Boundaries, Aging Magician, Five Beats, and Sandhills Reunion.
  The website features a biography, upcoming events, a discography, contact information, and a list of works.
- Edwards, Ryan, April 2014-July 2021; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of ryanedwards.info in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The composer's website contained a biography of the artist, information about his compositions and projects, and examples of his works in the form of embedded image and video files. In 2021, the website redirected to an adult dating website and crawling was turned off.
  Embedded image files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played. Embedded YouTube and Vimeo videos were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Ryan Edwards is a Boston-based composer of West African and jazz influenced dance music. He also produces multimedia performance and installation works through Masary Studios, a transdisciplinary artist collective he co-founded with Sam Okerstrom-Lang.
- Ehrlich, Marty, June 2017-January 2019; cuid5944; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of martyehrlich.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website was captured three times between 2017 and 2019. It contained a biography of the artist; information about his compositions and projects; news and reviews about Ehrlich; a gallery of images of the artist; a calendar of his events; and examples of his works in the form of embedded audio and video files. As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist, events listings, information about the Julius Hemphill Archive at NYU, and contact information.
  Parts of the live site involving Flash were not captured due to technological constraints.
  Marty Ehrlich (b. 1955) is a New York City-based saxophonist, clarinetist, flutist, and composer of jazz-influenced pieces incorporating improvisation for large and small ensembles. He is the founder of the Emergency Peace Ensemble and worked extensively with composer and saxophonist Julius Hemphill. In 1996, Ehrlich became the director of Hemphill's Sextet after Hemphill's death and Ehrlich is also the chief researcher for the Julius Hemphill Archives housed at New York University. Examples of notable works by Ehrlich include The Long View and A Trumpet in the Morning.
  Marty Ehrlich Quartet; Marty Ehrlich Large Ensemble
- Eisenberg, Jewlia, February 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://charminghostess.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; a visual timeline of her life and work; information about Charming Hostess; information about her compositions and projects; a calendar of her events; press excerpts about Eisenberg and her projects; a discography of her published albums; and examples of her works in the form of embedded audio and video files.
  Jewlia Eisenberg (1970-2021) was an American composer, singer, bassist, educator, and founding member of the group Charming Hostess. Through her compositions, she aimed to explore the full expressive capabilities of the human voice.
  Charming Hostess (Musical group)
- Eötvös, Melody, December 2016-ongoing; Eötvös, Melody, 1984-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of melodyeotvos.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Melody Eötvös (b. 1984) is a composer of contemporary classical music who creates works for solo, chamber, orchestra, vocal, and multimedia. Eötvös' pieces include the use of traditional instrumentation as well as electro-acoustic sound art. Recent works by Eötvös include Bachgram for solo piano; In the Fire for mezzo soprano and piano; Shivelight for horn trio; At every instant, one must fly for violin and harp; and When Pine Cones Fall in Perfect Circles, for solo guitar.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist, a list of works with score samples, news, and contact information.
- Etezady, Roshanne, February 2015-March 2021; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of roshanne.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Roshanne Etezady (b. 1973) is a composer of contemporary classical music. Etezady's musical background was originally as a pianist and flutist. Her interest in becoming a composer of contemporary classical music was inspired by Philip Glass and his ensemble's performance on the television show Saturday Night Live in 1986. Etezady's musical compositions combine lyricism with rhythmic intensity. Her discography includes the titles Breath Beneath, Glint, Wild Nights!, Harvest, Oncoming Traffic, and Breaking Training.
  The website features news, reviews, an audio gallery, a biography, contact information, a store, and her discography.
- Evans, Michael, April 2014-June 2023; Evans, Michael (Drummer); 1 websites in 1 archived website